smartkpis.com 2019-04-04

# Privacy Statement | The KPI Institute

The KPI Institute Pty.Ltd is committed to protecting your privacy. This Data Privacy policy outlines our personal information handling practices, for both online and offline data. If you give us personal information, we will treat it with the utmost care and never sell, rent or share your personal information with third parties under any circumstances.

This policy applies to all The KPI Institute’s websites, including: [www.kpiinstitute.org](http://www.kpiinstitute.org/), [www.gpaunit.org](http://www.gpaunit.org/), <http://www.tkisolutions.com/>, <https://www.skills.ac/> and [www.performancemagazine.org](http://www.performancemagazine.org/), as well as to all extensions related to these web domains.

Please note that this Privacy Policy may change from time to time, though we expect most such changes to be minor. We will post any Policy changes on this page. We encourage you to read this privacy policy and take notice of how your data is being processed. By using The KPI Institute’s websites, you agree to the terms under this policy.

 **Who we are?**

The KPI Institute is a leading global research institute specialized in business performance. It operates research programs in 12 practice domains, ranging from strategy and KPIs to employee performance and from customer service to innovation performance. Insights are disseminated through a variety of publications, subscriptions services and through a knowledge platform available to registered members. Support in deploying these insights in practice is offered globally through training and advisory services.

The KPI Institute is considered today the global authority on Key Performance Indicators (KPIs) research and education. It developed the first KPI Management Framework and operates www.smartKPIs.com, the result of the research program dedicated to documenting and cataloguing how KPIs are used in practice, an online portal containing the largest collection of documented KPI examples.

The company headquarter is in Melbourne, Australia, located at: Life.lab Building 198 Harbour Esplanade, Suite 606, Melbourne Docklands, VIC 3008, Australia.

 **What does personal data refer to?**

Personal data means any information related to an identified or identifiable natural person. An identifiable natural person is one who can be identified, either directly, by name for example, or indirectly, by reference to an identifier such as: an unique identification number, location data, an online identifier, or one or more factors specific to the physical, physiological, genetic, mental, economic, cultural or social identity of that natural person.

Natural persons may be associated with online identifiers provided by their devices, applications, tools and protocols, such as internet protocol addresses, cookie identifiers or other identifiers.

Such examples of personal data include, but are not limited to: names, email addresses, phone numbers, profile photos, audio and video recordings, Twitter, Facebook, LinkedIn IDs and profile URLs, IPs (IPv4 and especially IPv6), biometric data like fingerprints, user agents, device names (like webcam names) or device IDs like MAC addresses, passport and social security numbers, driver’s license or ID photos, geolocation info, posts on social media, bank account & credit card information, PayPal IDs, SSH public keys.

 **What types of data do we collect and how?**

There are instances when The KPI Institute receives your data directly, via our websites and forms, as you create a new account, or you download a brochure or some free resources, or you subscribe to our newsletters, or you request a demo, or you buy a product / service from us, or you participate at our courses and events, or you send us your CV for a job opportunity, or you contact us. Such data includes, but it is not limited to: your name, e-mail address, home or work address, telephone number, date and place of birth, profile photo, job position and company name, qualifications and any other information specifically mentioned by you (feedback, correspondence etc).

In other instances, The KPI Institute collects automatically information about your computer hardware and software, in order to improve your experience on our websites. This information can include, but it is not limited to: your IP address (IPv4 and especially IPv6), browser type, domain names, access times and referring website addresses. To read more information about cookies and how we use them, please refer to the [Cookie Policy](https://kpiinstitute.org/cookie-policy). Also, in order to improve the customer experience, we automatically record client conversations, but we do not process data only in special circumstances, if needed.

You are not required to give us your personal data, but in this case, it will be almost impossible for us to provide you the information, products and services you expect from us.

 **How do we process your data?**

We do not share your personal data outside The KPI Institute, unless you give your consent to do so, or when the law requires it, or when you expect us to do so.

However, by providing personal information to The KPI Institute’s websites, you agree that such information may be stored outside your country or held by third parties providing services to The KPI Institute, but it will not be used by such third parties for their own purposes.

In case the data processing includes the transfer outside of the European Union, the transfer is based on EU approved standards and contractual clauses, thus ensuring an adequate level of personal data protection as requested by the applicable data protection law. We will transfer your data only to non-EU countries in relation to which the European Commission is confident that they provide an adequate level of data protection or international-transfers.

Please keep in mind that if you directly disclose your data through The KPI Institute’s websites, this information may be collected and used by others.  Also, The KPI Institute encourages you to review the privacy statements of the websites you choose to link to from The KPI Institute’s websites, so that you understand how those websites collect, use and share your information. The KPI Institute is not responsible for the privacy statements or other content available on websites outside The KPI Institute’s websites.

The KPI Institute collects and processes your personal data in order to provide you with the services you expect from us, either to give you access to our online resources, or to participate to our courses, events and webinars, or to receive promotional offers from us, latest news and insightful performance management articles, or to be part of our performance related surveys, or to find the right job/role for which you applied. An important aspect related to the promotional campaigns we send you, is that you can always update your preferences, by opting-in or out, at your choice.

Also, your data can be processed for administrative purposes related to the Certification process, or for finance related purposes related to the invoice issued, in case you have participated at one of our training programs, or you have purchased one of our products and services.

Your data can be used without further consent for non-marketing purposes, such as notifying you of major website changes or for customer service purposes, or in order to comply to the law requirements

The most common communication channels we use include, but are not limited to: emails, phone calls, messages, posts and face-to-face meetings. Your data will be only processed the authorized departments, meant to ensure the achievement of the services you expect from us. Such departments include, but are not limited do: Digital Marketing, Customer services, Educational Programs, Customer Engagement, Finance, Human Resources.

 **How long do we keep your data?**

We will keep your data, after having your prior consent, for an unlimited period of time, as long as you have an account on our websites, or you are subscribed to our newsletters, or you have in any other way provided your data to us, until you withdraw your consent or unsubscribe from our newsletters or you ask us to delete your data from our database.

We may keep some personal data to comply with national and international legal requirements, as in the case of internal information about our employees, for historical and statistical data.

If we have to delete your data, this means that we cannot process it any longer and use it to inform you about any of our events, products, services or job opportunities. In case you want to provide your data again in the future, you will have to register again with us.

 **Your rights**

You are entitled to contact us in case you want to:

  * Be informed about how we use your data;
  * Receive access and obtain a copy of the data we have about you;
  * Change or update your data, if you discovered that we have inaccurate / outdated information about you
  * Update your email marketing preferences, by opting-in or out from some or from all our newsletters;
  * Withdraw your consent on data processing;
  * Delete all the personal data we have about you;
  * Make a complaint to the data protection authority if you have any doubts regarding how we process your data;
  * Restrict our use of your data;
  * Transfer your data from our database to another one;
  * Disable Cookies – for more information about the Cookie Policy, read the entire policy [here](https://kpiinstitute.org/cookie-policy)

 **Contact us**

You can excise your rights by contacting The KPI Institute via email at: [dataoffice@kpiinstitute.org](mailto:dataoffice@kpiinstitute.org). Also, we are happy to receive any other inquiries related to your personal data at the above-mentioned email address.
